Praveen Choudhary (1) Featured

ReactJs Developer, Redux, Jsx, PHP, Laravel, HTML, Ajax, Jquery, CSS, MySQL



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Infinite Computer Solutions Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Gurgaon Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Noida, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Gurgaon Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: React.Js, Javascript, HTML, PHP, MySQL

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

I am a proficient developer having more than 7 year of professional experience in implementing Web Applications with focus on Usability, Implementation and testing and a track record of delivering quality solutions using range of different technologies.

Work Experience

Infinite Computer Solutions as Senior Software Engineer Aug 2020 to Till Date

Looking for a job on ReactJs Developer.

Vcare Corporation as Team Leader

May 2016 to Aug 2020

- Product Name: Telgoo5
- Module: Create API, Reports, CSR 0
- Technology: PHP, MYSQL 0
- Description: Telgoo5 product is based on Telecom Domain. Using this we maintain customer accounts. 0
- ? Product Name: Singer CRM
- Technology: PHP, MYSQLI 0
- URL: singer.vcarecorporation.com
- Description: Singer CRM is used for manage complaints against singer products. In it we have 5 type of user Admin, 0 Agent, RM, SF & Technician. Agent attend call from customer and register their complaint and assign to SF & Technician of that zone.
- ? Product Name: Kajaria CRM
- Technology: PHP, MYSQLI 0
- URL: kajaria.vcarecorporation.com
- Description: Kajaria CRM is used for manage complaints against kajaria products. In it we have 4 type of user Admin, Agent, RM & Technician. Agent attend call from customer and register their complaint and assign to Technician of that zone.
- Product Name: Kerovit CRM

- Technology: Laravel, MYSQL
- URL: kerovit.vcarecorporation.com
- Description: Kerovit CRM is used for manage complaints against kerovit products. In it we have 8 type of user Admin, Agent, VP, GM, RM, AM, Coordinator & Technician. Agent attend call from customer and register their complaint and assign to Coordinator & Technician of that area.

Flexsin Technology as PHP Developer

Aug 2014 to May 2016

- Project Name: Qualitas Flash Drives
- 0 Technology: WordPress, MYSQL
- URL: www.qualitasflashdrives.com 0
- Description: Qualitas is online Ecommerce website where you can design your Flash Drive and order. 0
- Project Name: PallMart
- Technology: WordPress, Amazon API, MYSQL O
- URL: www.pallmart.com 0
- Description: In Pallmart we fetch products from Amazon API and show on our website. 0
- Project Name: Online Gym web Application
- Technology: WordPress, jQuery, MYSQL O
- URL: www.surfersgym.com
- Description: In Surgersgym customers purchase membership for get Gym training online. After customer purchased O membership they able to access Exercise video according their number of day in class.

Techno Softwares as PHP Developer

Feb 2013 to Mar 2014

- Project Name: Instant Video
- Technology: PHP, HTML5 Canvas, jQuery, MYSQL O
- Description: Instant Video is a design tool where user can upload it's image and perform multiple operation like Rotate, Transparency, Move over another image, Write Text on image and also user can create it's own Template and download it in a Image.
- Project Name: Design Concepts
- Technology: HTML, ¡Query, CSS
- 0 URL: www.design-concepts.in
- Description: Design Concepts is a simple informative Website.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Rajasthan University in 2012

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Windows 10, DOS, Ubuntu	
MySQL	
PHP, WordPress, Laravel, HTML	
AJAX, Jquery, CSS	
React.js	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time